Burnable
Unburnable
Bulky
午前八時お弁当を作る
特に卵焼きは自信作
今日のためにやって程練習したんだもの
これを食べれば
彼の心は
08:00, making lunch.
I'm especially proud of my fried eggs.
お早う　晶ちゃん
After all, I've practiced endlessly for this day!
お早う
御免　寝過ごしちゃ
After one bite, his heart will...
なんでいるの
Morning, Sho.
Morning, I oversle―
くるくる回る
君の瞳探して回る
駅のホーム
Why are you here?!
響くファンファーレ
<< kurukuru mawaru kimi no hitomi >>
<< Round and round, your eyes wander around >>
ガラガラ音を立てる街
<< sagashite mawaru eki no home >>
<< Searching around the station's platforms >>
とりあえず耳を貸してみたの
<< hibiku fanfare >>
<< The sound of fanfare from afar >>
もうすぐ消えるはずの世界に
<< garagara oto wo tateru machi >>
<< The clamorous city making noise >>
<< toriaezu mimi wo kashite ita no >>
<< I tried to keep an ear out for all this >>
<< mousugu kieru hazu no sekai ni >>
<< In a world that's about to end >>
御免ね
もう二度と会えないようなそんな気がして
<< gomen ne >>
<< I'm sorry >>
運命が笑う
<< mou nido to aenai youna sonna ki ga shite >>
<< I just had a feeling I would never see you again >>
臨界点突破してる
限界なら既に去って
<< unmei ga warau >>
<< Fate is laughing at us >>
絶対的支配だって
崩壊
<< rinkaiten toppa shiten da >>
<< I'm already past the point of no return >>
終末理論は机上の空論でしかないって
<< genkai nara sude ni satte >>
<< Far over my limit >>
<< zettaiteki shihai datte >>
<< Even your absolute control has >>
ゼロとイチの世界線の果てから
<< houkai >>
<< Crumbled >>
<< shuumatsu riron wa kijou no kuuron shika naitte >>
<< "The end of the world is nothing but a hypothesis" >>
叫ぶよ
<< 0 to 1 no sekaisen no hate kara sakebu yo >>
<< Is what I'm crying out from other side of the binary world line >>
もうすぐ君が会いにくるような気がして
僕は目を閉じるよ
<< mou sugu kimi ga ai ni kuru you na ki ga shite >>
<< I have a feeling you'll come see me soon >>
本字幕由诸神字幕组(www.kamigami.org)制作,仅供学习交流之用
若您喜欢本作品,请支持正版影像制品
---诸神字幕组---
日听 xHunter 翻译：英英 校对：凌可乐
时间轴：绯桜闲   压制：笑眯眯的妖精
<< boku wa me wo tojiru yo >>
<< So I will be waiting with my eyes closed >>
Gourmet Kings
in my city!
Let's introduce another gourmet item we found in the city today.
さあー　今朝の早速　街並みかけた美味しいものご紹介しましょう
Tada!
ジャン　特製豪楽弁当デラックス完成です
Special Deluxe Picnic Lunch is done!
Good for you, Ringo!
よかったね　リンゴちゃん
Yeah!
うん
Where are you taking it, anyway?
ところでさ　それ何処に持って行くの
For a date, right? Ringo?
デートだよね　リンゴちゃん
Yes...
うん
She asked me to teach her how to make tasty fried eggs, but I didn't know how.
美味しい卵焼きの作り方を教えてって頼まれたんだけど
私じゃ上手くいかなくて
晶ちゃんが手伝ってくれだから　本当助かっちゃった
You were a great help, Sho!
Oh? That's good.
そう　それはよかった
全然よくないよ
It's not nice at all!
It must be for Tabuki.
相手って多蕗だろう
That's stalking, not a date!
それはデートじゃなくてストーキングって言うだよ
Oh! This is really good!
上手く出来出るじゃ　さすが我が家の主夫
You're living up to the role of a housewife.
誰が主夫だって
Who are you calling a housewife?
By the way, where are you going bird watching today?
とろこで　荻野目さん　今日はどこで野鳥の観察をするの
Watazuka Park.
和田塚公園
What a coincidence!
やー　偶然だな　晶馬も今日そこで用事があるだよ
Shoma is going there today too!
Right, Shoma?
なな　晶馬
Huh?
Hey, what do you mea―
ちょっと　どういう
いいか　隙を見てあの女の鞄を探れ
Check her bag when you get an opportunity, got it?
Find the item.
例の物を見つけるだよ
What about you, Bro?
で　兄貴は
I-I have some business to take care of.
俺はちっと野暮用
It's all you today.
今日のところはお前に任せた
健闘を祈る
I wish you good luck!
A girl again?
また女の子　兄貴そのうち本当に天罰が下るよ
You're due for some divine retribution some day.
Yeah, right.
言ってろう
Okay, Oginome?
ね　荻野目さん
...Stolen skunk has been sighted.
Birdie
盗み出されたスカンクを見かけたとの情報があり
Smelly and dangerous "pet"
Planned theft?
The police are currently investigating the scene.
駆けつけた警察により捜索が行われております
Residents of the area, please do not attempt to capture Kiyoshi if you see him.
近くに御住まいの皆様
Kiyoshi, Age 1
キヨシ君を見かけたら　絶対に捕獲はせらず
Contact the police immediately.
まずは警察にご連絡を
Skunk sighted
Because Kiyoshi, the skunk, is...
と言いますのもスカンクのキヨシ君は
Hey, you're going to the park to go bird watching, right?
あのさ　今日は公園に野鳥を見に行くだよね
Yes.
そうよ
Is that, like...
なんで言うか　それも　あのう
Fate or something?
運命だったりするわけ
What?
ええ
Uh, well... you mentioned something like that last time.
いや
なんかこの間そんなようなこと言ってたからさ
Today's
Slogan
Yes.
そうよ
What's about to happen today is... destiny.
今日これから起こることは運命
Beware of luggage theft
It's a very important mission of mine.
とても大事なミッションなの
Failure is not an option.
失敗は許されないわ
I see.
そうなんだ
Takakura house - Night - Living room - *Brothers in secret meeting. What's the connection between Ringo and Penguin Drum? #2's head is hot, but endures.
She said something about, "fate already written down," right?
あの女運命は記されているって言ってたよな
In other words, it's written in a book, a notebook, or on some kind of paper?
つまり本とかノートとか何か紙に書いてあるってこと
Yeah, we can assume that's the case.
ああ　そう考えていいだろう
The question is, how does it relate to the Penguin Drum we're after?
それが俺たちのピングドラムとどう関係するのか
In any case, it must be the key to solving our problem.
とにかく　謎を解く鍵はそこにあるはずだ
We haven't come across it in our search so far.
これまでの捜索で見つかれなかったってことは
That probably means she's holding on to it at all times.
恐らくあの女肌に離さず隠し持っているだろう
The problem is getting it.
それをどうするかだが
Could it be inside that bag?
もしかして　あの中に
HSK's next performance
Tragedy of M
Fated Love
HSK's next performance
be allowed?
Will their "love"
Fated Love
be allowed?
Will their "love"
Fated love?!
運命の恋
Dazzling the stage, Prince Tabuki!
多蕗王子様のおなり
Sorry for making you wait, my princess.
お待たせ　我が姫よ
Today is a commemorable day for us.
今日は君と僕との記念すべき大事な日
Fear not.
さあ　どうか怖がらないで
Let us go forth to the Eden of eternal happiness!
いざりゅぱん　我らが二人至福の楽園へ
Yes, I'll come with you!
ええ　おともしますわ
I'll follow you to the ends of the earth!
おともしますわ　何処までも
Watazuka Park
10:00, meet up by the fountain.
午前十時噴水広場で待ち合わせ
Right on time, as planned.
計画通り　完璧
I'll be going, then.
それじゃ　あたしはここで
あ　いや　待ち合わせ場所まで持って行くよ
Uh... I'll carry it for you...
Why?
どうして
Why? Because...
どうしてって
ええと
なんだあれ
What's that?
What's this? It stinks!
何これ　臭い　臭い　臭い
What should I do, what do I do?!
どうしよう　　どうしたらいい
I have to do something important, something I have to do!
これから大事な事があるのに
絶対やらなきゃいけないことがあるのに
そんなこと言われたって
What am I supposed to do about it?
You really stink!
君本当に臭い
Tabuki is coming...
多蕗さんが来ちゃう　服取り替えて
Give me your clothes!
そんなことで誤魔化せるのか
Can you really fool him with that?
Thanks for waiting!
やあ　お待たせ
It really is Tabuki.
やっぱり多蕗だ
He's got zero fashion sense! Not that I care.
どうでもいいけど
私服ダサい
うん　今日は彼氏も一緒かな
You brought your boyfriend with you today?
彼氏
B-Boyfriend?
そんなじゃ全然ないんです
It's not like that, at all!
He's just a friend, but he insisted on coming today after hearing about it.
あの人はただの知り合いで
でも今日のことを話したらどうしても自分も行きたいって聞かなくって
He's really annoying, isn't he?
本当に　ご迷惑ですよね　御免なさい
I'm sorry!
いいや　野鳥好きの仲間なら　何時でも大歓迎だよ
No, I look forward to meeting fellow bird lovers any time!
Oh, it's you, Takakura!
なんだ　高倉じゃないか
Hi, Mr. Tabuki.
どうも　先生
He's a student of mine.
高倉は僕のクラスの生徒なんだ
I didn't know you two knew each other.
二人は知り合いだったのか　奇遇だな
What a coincidence!
But is it just me, or do I smell...
ところで　気のせいかな
どうも先から妙な匂いが
この人です　臭いのはこの人です
It's him!
He's the one who stinks!
ええ
He fell in a pile of manure yesterday!
この人昨日肥溜めに落ちたんです
Not only that, he jumped into a turtle pond that hasn't been cleaned for six months!
おまけには今朝は半年間洗っていなかった亀の水槽の水を被って
臭いから　来ないって言ったのに
I told him not to come because he stinks, but he refuses to listen!
全く利く意味持たなくて
本当物凄い迷惑してるです　御免なさい
He's such a stalker! I'm sorry he followed me!
That's a pity, even though he's wearing such a cute T-shirt.
御洒落なシャツを着てるのに　それは残念だな
Oh, we're with a cute couple today.
あら　今日はまた可愛いらしいカップルとご一緒なのね
Good timing! I have an old friend to introduce to you two.
ちょっとよかった　僕も古い友人を紹介するよ
Yuri Tokikago.
時籠百合さんだ
Nice to meet you.
はじめまして
Ringo - Tabuki's apartment - In front of Tabuki's room - *Frightening reality faces Ringo. I wanted to forget it. Yes, that woman was in his room.
Would you like some curry?
さあ　これはいかが
美味しいよ
It's delicious!
Isn't she beautiful?
美人だろう　実は彼女女優さんでね
She's actually an actress.
She's the prima donna of the Sunshiny Opera Troupe...
サンシャイン歌劇団で娘役を
あのう　失礼ですが
E-Excuse me, are you Miss Yuri Tokikago, from the second troupe?
時籠百合さんっていらっしゃいますよね　虹組の
Yes.
ええ
Wow! I'm honored to meet you!
お目にかかれて光栄です
次回公演のマリ役超楽しみにしてます　頑張ってください
I can't wait to see you play Marie in the next performance!
I hope it goes well.
Marie's role?
マリ役
I'm an actress.
私は女優　その星の下生まれた
Born to be one.
Like a rose blossoming at the center stage.
舞台に咲き誇る一輪の薔薇の花
I have everyone's attention.
ああ　誰もが私を見て
They all gasp at my beauty.
ため息を漏らすのファビュラスマックス
Fabulous max!
What's with this ridiculous development?
ちょっと　なんなのよ　この展開は
This is my daydream!
これは私のイリュージョン
中止　中止や
Stop, stop it!
But there's only one person in my heart.
でも私の心は一つあの方に捧げるの
It's all for him.
それは素敵な鳥の王子様
He's a wonderful Bird Prince.
I'm an actress.
私は女優　私は女優
Oh, thank you.
あら　嬉しいわ
Are you serious?
マジかよ
ありがとう
Thank you.
Coffee and a Surprise Chocolate Sundae?
コーヒーとビッグりチョクサンデーがお一つですね
It'll be right out.
少少お待ちください
I know what you're looking for.
If you want to know more about it, meet me tomorrow at
the restaurant as shown in the map below, at 11:00.
Who else knows about us?
一体誰が俺たちの事
There must be others going after the Penguin Drum too.
他にもピングドラムを狙ってる奴がいるのか
Or could it be...
それとも
Hello.
こんにちは
It's been a while.
お久しぶり
Kanba.
冠葉君
Ka-n-ba!
冠　葉　君
Damn it, I fell for it.
くそ　やられた
We formed the Association of Romantic Victims of Kanba Takakura.
私たち高倉冠葉恋愛被害者の会議を作ったから
Kuho called us to join.
久宝さんが呼びかけてくれたの
Asami did?
阿佐美が
そうよ　あなたに騙されてる可哀相な女の子を集めて抗議活動することにしたの
We're gathering the poor girls deceived by you to protest!
We'll going to get you to take responsibility...
今日こそ純情な乙女心を玩んだ責任
きっちりつけてもらいます
for toying with our pure hearts.
This must be divine retribution!
天罰だ
They flew away again.
また逃げられちゃったか
I'm sorry, it must be this smelly guy's fault.
御免なさい　きっとこの臭い人のせいですよね
Well...
マアー
Let's make it a casual walking date today.
なら今日は気楽のお散歩でことにしましょよ
It's been a while since I had the time to relax like this.
このところ新作の稽古に掛り切りで
I've been so busy rehearsing for the new play.
こんなにのんびりしたのは久しぶり
Thank you for inviting me to come, Tabuki.
誘ってくれて　ありがとう　多蕗君
It's not a big deal...
いいや　僕は何も
I won't lose to you!
負けないわよ　私には特製豪楽弁当デラックスがあるだから
I have the Special Deluxe Picnic Lunch!
Let's destiny!
レツ　デスティニー
あのう　そろそろお昼にしませんか
Say, how about we have lunch soon?
No!
いいややー
The... the lunch I made...
私の　私の御弁当が
It's your fault!
あなたのせいよ
ええ　僕
My fault?!
You told me to leave it there because I smell!
だって　臭くなるからお弁当をそこに置けって君が言ったんじゃないか
You're the one who said it!
How are you going to fix this?
どうしてくれるよ
My plan is ruined!
それが計画が台無し
We have to eat lunch at 12:30!
私たちは十二時までお昼を食べなきゃいけないの
You don't have to worry.
それだったら　心配いらないと思うわ
Wow!
凄い　これ全部百合さんが
Did you make all of this?
Yes, I just made it from leftovers in my fridge, so...
ええ　朝冷蔵庫の余りもので作っただけだから
It can't possibly compare to Ringo's lunch.
到底リンゴちゃんの弁当には敵えそうにないけど
嘘つき
Liar!
You probably just bought this from a store and repacked it!
どうせ全部デパ地下とかで買ってつめてきたでしょ
Let's dig in!
頂きます
うん　美味しい
This is great!
Here you go.
サアー　どうぞ
Thank you.
や　ありがとう
Here.
サアー　あなたも一ついかが
Why don't you have a taste?
If they have no bread, let them eat cake.
パンがないというなら
ケーキを食べればいいじゃない
Go take a fabulous lunch!
テイクアウト
ファビュラスランチ
Enjoy my homemade lunch.
さあ　私の手作り召し上がれ
Oh! How très bien!
おお　なんと
This is truly Sunshiny Miracle!
これぞ正にサンシャニミラクル
This is such a beautiful lunch.
The such a beautiful lunch
How about an octopus-shaped wiener?
さあ　タコさんウインナーはいかが
Plenty of sweets too!
スィーツだってご用意しててよ
"12:30, lunch with Tabuki."
十二時半　多蕗君と御弁当を食べる
"He said it was delicious and smiled."
美味しいと喜んでくれた
No problem, it's still going as planned.
大丈夫
予定通り　運命はまだ私の見方
Fate is still on my side.
15:00, I've practically won already, just as long as I can accomplish this mission!
午後三時　このミッションさえクリア-すればもう私が勝ったもう当然
The kiss of the prince!
王子様の口づけは
The secret plan I'm about to tell you,
これから話す　秘密の計画
our fate is written here.
運命はここに書いてある
15:00, he squeezes me, and breathes on my neck!
午後三時　ぎゅうとされ　吐息が首筋に
My heart is going to explode!
ドキドキ
Hey, Ringo.
ね　リンゴちゃん　その計画教えて教えて
Tell me about that plan, please, please?
そんなに知りたい
Do you really want to know?
Yes, I do, I do!
うん　知りたい知りたい
秘密はこれ
This is the secret!
Wow, it looks tasty!
わ　美味しそう
The princess is scared of the caterpillar.
毛虫を怖がる御姫様
The prince saves her.
王子様が助けるの
His hand clasps her shoulder.
触れ合うかだ当然
Their eyes meet.
見詰め合う眼差しならら
La la la.
Then they fall in love.
そして二人は恋に落ちるの
That's destiny.
それがデスティニー
Then...
そして
"Rose of Versailles" was packed today!
今日のベルサイは大変な人出ですこと
My chance!
チャンス
No! A dreadful caterpillar on my shoulder!
ああ　恐ろしい毒毛虫があたしの肩に
Brave prince! Please save this poor girl!
どうか　勇気のある王子　哀れの娘にお助けを
Oh, no!
これはいけない
I must save her!
助けなくては
Yes, prince! Save me!
そうよ　王子様　早くこちに来て
You're mine!
頂きます
Oh, no! Prince, the princess is...
王子　大変です
王妃様が
Oh, a caterpillar!
ああ　毛虫
Ignore that peasant and save her!
そうな平民はほっとおいて　早くこちらへ
What? Wait...
ええ　ちょっと
Come with me to a drugstore. Let's go buy an ointment!
サア　ご一緒に薬局へ虫ケロリンを買いに参りましょう
はい
Yes.
Hairy beast, you must be a spy for the revolutionary regime!
毛深い奴め　サデオ革命政府スパイアか
Uh... wait!
あのう　ちょっと
Don't squeeze or breathe down my neck!
ぎゅうと首筋に吐息をやめて
By the way, thank you for the curry the other day.
そういえばこの間のカレー　ご馳走様
It wasn't all that bad.
まあまあだったわね　多蕗君も褒めてたわよ
Tabuki was praising it.
"Your cooking is wonderful, Yuri."
百合の料理は美味しいねって
Oh, I disposed of your shoes, so don't worry.
ああ　それと貴方の靴ちゃんと処分しておいたから　安心して
Let's keep this our little secret.
このことは二人だけの秘密にしておきましょ
But...
でも　貴方に勝ち目はないと思うけど
I don't think you stand a chance against me.
Are you okay? Does it hurt?
大丈夫　痛くない
Thanks for worrying about me.
ありがとう　ちょっとビリットするだけだから
Ointment
It just stings a little.
No problem, I still have time.
大丈夫　時間はまだある
"Meeting at 10:00."
十時に待ち合わせ
"Lunch at 12:30."
十二時半にお弁当
"Breathes on me at 3:00 and heart explodes?"
三時は吐息がかかってドキドキ
What the heck is this?
何じゃこれや　今日の予定
Today's plan?
"4:00, first kiss by the pond?!"
四時　池の畔で初めてのキス
There's only 15 minutes left for that.
あと十五分しかないじゃないか
But...
だけど
There's no way that's going to happen the way things are now.
とてもじゃないけど　そんなムードじゃないわ
I'll do it!
わたしやるわ
I'll kiss Tabuki by 4:00, no matter what!
絶対四時に多蕗さんとキスする
Destiny!
デスティニー
Um...
あ　あのう
Save me!
助けて　助けて
Princess Ringo!
リンゴ姫
ああ　なんということだ
How could this have happened?
To break the evil witch's spell, this is my only choice!
邪悪な魔女の魔法を破るにはこれしかない
Love will save the world.
愛は世界を救う
Yes, Ringo.
そうよ　リンゴ　勇気を出して
Muster up your courage.
It's always the fearless and brave princess who wins the prince in fairy tales!
おとぎ話で王子様勝ち取るのは
いつだって危険を恐れない　勇敢な御姫様なんだから
Let's destiny!
レツ　デスティニー
Tabuki?!
多蕗さん　い　いない
He's gone!
Baby chicks become really attached to people when...
鶏はね　戸外にすると人によく慣れて
Is this a diary?
日記
Does that mean her fate is written down in here?
ここにあの子の運命が記されてるってこと
For real?
これが本当に
Save me!
助けて　誰が
Someone!
ああ　私このまま死ぬのかな
Am I just going to die like this?
I couldn't kiss Tabuki...
多蕗さんとキス出来なかったよ
I'm sorry Mom, I couldn't follow my fate...
御免ね　ママ
私　運命守れなかった
I wonder what Dad is doing.
パパ　どうしてるかな
Just one last time...
最後に　もう一度会いたいな
I want to see him...
Ringo?
リンゴちゃん　リンゴちゃん
Ringo!
I'm so relieved!
良かった
I...
わたし
You fell in the pond and nearly drowned.
池に落ちて溺れたんだ
You really gave me a scare.
一時はどうなるかと
You got CPR right away...
すっぐに人口呼吸したんだけど
CPR?
人口呼吸
ああ　あのお姉ちゃん先お兄ちゃんとちゅうしてたんだよ
That girl was kissing that boy earlier!
Don't say something like that, Ken!
こら　兼ちゃん　やめなさい
ああ　私　多蕗さんと
Tabuki and me?
I kissed Tabuki!
多蕗さんとキスしたんだ
Damn it, why did I have to go through all this?
くそ　どうして僕がこんな目に
You saved the day.
大活躍だったわね　救命員さん
Mr. Lifeguard.
偉いわ
It was so admirable.
You jumped in the pond, and even gave her CPR!
池に飛び込んで　おまけに人口呼吸まで
You were really wonderful.
カッコ良かったわよ
Why did I do it?!
やってしまった
Akasaka Mitsuke Station
a girl in red heels.
Yes, but was it really for the best?
はい　でもあれで良かったんでしょか
I feel like I made him think I'm a troublesome woman.
何だがかえって面倒な女だって思われてしまったようで
What are you talking about? We must crush him at once.
いやじゃの　早くすり潰さないと
What?
Don't worry.
大丈夫　それも計画の一輪
It's part of the plan.
So don't be concerned.
だから心配なさらないで
I've already set up our next move.
もう次の手は打ってある
But... what's our next move?
だけど　次の手って一体何を
21:00, Akasaka Mitsuke Station, the girl in red heels on the escalator...
午後九時　赤坂見つけ駅
エスカレータ　赤い靴の女の子
a girl in red heels.
Akasaka Mitsuke Station
That's all for today.
今日はこれでお終い
a girl in red heels.
Destiny.
デスティニー
Descension of a Princess
subete ga moshi kimerarete tara
If everything was written in stone
全てが欲しい
繋がれたいたら
bokura wa doushite mogaku no darou
Why have we been resisting our fate?
僕らはどうして
もがくのだろう
sore wa kimi ja nai
It's not you
それは君じゃない
君のせいじゃない
kimi no sei ja nai
It's not your fault
kanashimi wa mou takusan nanda
I've had enough misery
苦しみはもう沢山なんだ
dakara sou ja nai
You're mistaken
だからそうじゃない
夢のままじゃない
ima no mama ja nai
Fate can be changed
上手く伝えきれないけど
umaku tsutaekirenai kedo
I can't explain it, but
Dear my future
Dear your future
良かったら　あのノート貸してもらえるかな
Can you let me borrow that notebook?
ほんのちょっとの間でいいんだ
Just for a while.
用が済んだら　すっぐ返すから
I'll return it to you when I'm done with it.
Shall we initiate...
the Survival Strategy?
Lily Hoshino